# Luke McConnell

(321) 317 - 2736

lukermcconnell@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/luke-mcconnell | https://github.com/lrmcc

#### **Personal Statement**

I am a Software Engineer with an interdisciplinary perspective. My experience in specific areas of engineering has honed my analytical skills and instilled straightforward methods of problem-solving. I have a desire to learn, design, and bring software systems of increasing scope into fruition.

### **Technical Skills**

- Programming: C#, Java, Python, C++
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, MacOS
- Server-side / DBMS: ASP.NET, MSSQL Server
- Documentation: LaTex, Adobe

- Web Dev: HTML, CSS, Javascript, React.JS
- Version-Control: Git, Azure DevOps
- Scripting: Bash, Powershell
- Other: Excellent Oral and Written Communication

## **Professional Experience**

Computer Scientist - U.S. Air Force Civilian Service, Colorado Springs, CO

August 2020 - Present

- Designed Enterprise-Level software for space ground systems applications.
- Contributed code and expertise to professional Agile software projects.
- Created stories and completed development tasks using Azure DevOps.
- Drafted and critiqued peer-reviewed Acceptance Test Procedures.
- Used Virtual Machines and custom emulators to conduct software maintenance.
- Composed automated scripts to configure Microsoft services and install custom software packages.
- Authored software requirements, technical documentation, and configuration management.
- Conducted formal and ad-hoc software testing.
- Effectively communicated technical information to team members and supervisors.
- SECRET Security Clearance (Issued: April 2021).

Nuclear Gauge Calibration Technician - InstroTek, Inc., Denver, CO

**January 2017 - August 2018** 

- Performed calibrations, repairs, and preventative maintenance on nuclear moisture-density gauges.
- Validated/updated software on a variety of gauges with EEPROM systems.
- Used tech manuals/oscilloscope to diagnose/repair surface-mount and through-hole electrical circuit boards.
- Conducted business transactions and internal data tracking with business and shipping software.

Nuclear Plant Operator - U.S. Navy, Yokosuka, Japan; Norfolk, VA

December 2010 - December 2016

- Safely operated all aspects of an aircraft carrier's nuclear reactor mechanical and fluid systems.
- Led small teams with various backgrounds through complex operating and maintenance procedures.
- Trained on-watch sailors during nuclear plant casualty scenarios for qualifications and proficiency.
- Awarded Navy & Marine Corps Achievement Medal, Humanitarian Service Medal. Honorable Discharge.
- SECRET Security Clearance (Lapsed: December 2018).

### **Education**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science
University of Colorado Boulder - GPA: 3.504
Associate of Science, Cum Laude
Community College of Denver - GPA: 3.65
NABCEP Solar Associate-Level Certification
Solar Ready Vets / OSHA 30 Program
Qualified Navy Nuclear Mechanical Operator
U.S. Navy Nuclear Power Training Pipeline

August 2018 - August 2020

**January 2017 - August 2018** 

October 2016 - November 2016

March 2011 - November 2012